Sisi Freeley

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I have been a pharmacist for 6 years. I truly value the positive impact we make in the healthcare field. I am transitioning my career goals to make a positive impact in many other ways as a full stack software developer.

My interest in programming was sparked when I was witness to the launch of an electronic health record at my previous place of work. I was very interested in how the software affected the user experience and translated into patient safety and outcomes.

There are many aspects of pharmacy that I genuinely enjoy including problem-solving, working as a team while under pressure, being adaptable, and being a life-long learner. I hope to bring these traits and more into the software development field where the possibilities are endless.

CONTACT ME:



813 454 3218



152 Sycamore Hill Drive Clarksville, TN 37042



liusi33@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/sisifreeley



github.com/sfreeley



sfreeley.github.io

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Developer | May 2020 - present

University of Florida

Doctor of Pharmacy | Graduated in 2014 -Graduated with Honors

University of South Florida

BS Biomedical Sciences | Graduated 2010

- Graduated with Honors

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Bootcamp

Nashville Software School | May 2020 - present

This six month, full-time, rigorous software development course will cover both front-end development foundations (including a focus on HTML, CSS, and JavaScript) as well as server-side development foundations using C# and .NET stack.

- Creating our individual single page app front-end capstone projects using JavaScript, fundamental concepts of functional components and React Hooks
- Implementing and practicing full CRUD functionality through the use of modular JavaScript, React library, and CSS
- Recognizing how to manipulate data through data relationships utilizing JSON and Postman as well as creating ERDs and the utilization of various external APIs and object oriented programming
- -Continuously improving on debugging, organizational, and problem-solving skills via multiple group and individual projects
- Continuously improving on team programming skills involving mastering usage of version control through the use of Git, GitHub, and improving on remote team learning and programming
- Continuously improving on software development planning, including the implementation of dependency graphs as well as wireframes with Sketchboard
- -Continuously working and improving on usage of Reactstrap, Bootstrap, and CSS

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS

TrackRx JavaScript | React | Reactstrap | Cloudinary

Front end Capstone Project | August 2020

Inspired by my experience as a pharmacist, and understanding that patients have a very difficult time managing multiple medications for multiple disease states, as well as understanding the reasons behind taking certain medications, and making sense of large amounts of information coming from their medical providers and pharmacists, this application sought to help alleviate some of this confusion.

- Users can document the drug name, dosage, dosage form, their patient specific directions, indication, and patient specific notes all in one place. They are also able to input prescription numbers and refills (if applicable) as well as last fill date and days supply, which will then automatically calculate their next refill date. A running, real-time countdown (by days) until next refill date for each individual medication will also be displayed to prevent users from running out of their medication.
- Through the use of functional components and React Hooks, CRUD functionality was achieved and users are able to perform each of these functions on each medication entry.
- Search functionality was enabled to allow users to search for specific keywords pertaining to their medications

Sisi Freeley

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS, CONTINUED

- Database fetch calls from JSON allowed manipulation of user specific data relationships.
- Users are able to upload any image (ie bottle, pill picture, reminders) and attach it to their medication entry for future reference (made possible through Cloudinary)
- Users are able to select various resources regarding multiple health topics pertinent to their disease states through the use of health.gov external API
- Reactstrap was used to implement each medication card and multiple modals, tabs, and popups.
 - https://github.com/sfreeley/front-end-capstone

GROUP PROJECTS

Nutshell JavaScript | React | CSS

Front end Group Project | August 2020

A social platform application that allows the user to interact with other users and communicate through posting public chats/messages, events, and articles, as well as viewing their own reminder tasks list

This project was completed once using vanilla JavaScript prior to using the React library. At that time I was responsible for login/registration page as well as tasks section; with React library I was responsible for CRUD functionality of messages and part of friends section)

- 1. Full CRUD functionality achieved through utilizing extensive JavaScript with modular code using functional components and React Hooks
- 2. Full wireframe using Sketchboard
- 3. dbdiagram for entity relationship diagram
- 4. Data storage and relationships with JSON server
- 5. CSS styling

https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-41/react-nutshell-the-hazelnuts

EXPERIENCE, CONTINUED

Pharmacist

Madigan Army Medical Center | July 2015-May 2019

- Experienced and proficient with the following healthcare technologies:
 - o MHS Genesis: Department of Defense newly launched EHR
 - o CHCS: Unix based legacy EHR
 - o ScriptPro: Pharmacy automation/workflow management software and robotics including filling, verifying, and dispensing
 - o GSL: Prescription storage and tracking RFID technology
- Responsibilities:
 - Initiated Narcan dispensing to at-risk opioid patients according to Madigan Naloxone Protocol
 - Presented in-services on pediatric medication dosing to Family Medicine providers
 - Co-wrote 'New Employee CHCS training manual' for new employees
 - Worked directly with providers as in-clinic pharmacist clarifying prescriptions and answering clinical questions
 - Verified accuracy of adult and pediatric compounded medications
 - Worked with inpatient pharmacist team to accurately and efficiently fill, dispense, and counsel on discharge medications
 - Acted as Pharmacist In-charge at various outlying clinics
 - Staying up-to-date on guidelines to best offer drug information and clinical recommendations to prescribers and patients
 - Screened and prevented adverse drug reactions of dispensed medications
 - Verified correct renal dosing and appropriateness of dispensed medications
 - Contacted providers to resolve various prescription issues
 - Worked in conjunction with clinical pharmacists to ensure dispensing of most optimal drug therapy and improved patient outcomes
 - Facilitated improved communication between healthcare providers and patients at various clinics by streamlining pharmacy workflow and resolution of problems
 - Counseling patients, inputting, filling, verifying, transferring prescriptions